## Louis Lawrence Nwadike

080-800-364-05, 081-361-204-51

<u>Luisvelawrence@gmail.com</u> <u>villetrex@gmail.com</u> <u>lawrenceHilary98@gmail.com</u> Abuja, FCT Nigeria 900101

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Extensive knowledge in computer science with multiple work experiences. Indepth knowledge in programming, software development, website design and development, ethical hacking, graphics design, computer engineering (computer maintenance and repairs), and networking. Consistently use in-depth knowledge of budgetary issues affecting development and implementation to create cost-effective solutions. Comfortable discussing technical issues and solutions with scientists and analysts as well as clients.

### **EXPERIENCES**

# **SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Dubai

(Kingmakers Supersports Dubai Turing Contract)

Jan 2022-present

- Built interactive web-based interfaces leveraging Typescript, Nextjs, React, react-native, React Query, Scss, Mui, Axios interceptors, Graphql, terraform iac with Azure subscription.
- I functioned as the lead senior developer in developing 'Superpicks' which is an app for sports betting and gaming used in multiple countries and locales.
- Functioned as the lead and only developer who developed the fantasy app as a subsidiary of Superkicks application. Also worked as a senior developer with other developers in creating the Predictor app which is also a subsidiary of Superpicks app.
- Developed flowCharts and layouts to identify software requirements and solutions.
- Automated system tasks using scripts and support tools. (superpicks.com)

#### **SENIOR FullStack Developer**

USA

(Science Corp Turing Contract)

June 2021-Nov 2021

- Developed and maintained website for Science corp which is a startup that aims to to solve medical issues especially problems of eyesite using machines and artificial intelligence.
- Developed the client side application using nextjs, next-auth, and react-query.
- Assisted Devops team with app cicd to Github, Herokuu and Azure devops
- Worked as a team to develop application backend using Ruby on Rails and Postgres database
- Worked on several microservices including Helix-Foundry, Helix Animals and Helix-wafers

(Science Scorp)

### **SENIOR SOLUTIONS ENGINEER**

NY

(Layer0)

Feb 2021-Jan 2022

• Developed optimization frameworks using nodejs, chrio, typescript, mongodb and reactjs,react-native

- Created server/client-side applications using nextis.
- Monitored entire software lifecycles to meet project specifications and deadlines.
- Analyzed and interpreted complex technical documents and data models.
- Worked with cross-functional teams to communicate project requirements and proposals. (<u>layer0</u>)

#### SENIOR FULL-STACK ENGINEER

NY

(RefundCo)

Jan 2020-Jan 2021

- Developed and deployed serverless full stack applications in aws cdk, dynamodb, cognito idp, s3, cloudformation, route53, sns, vpc, ec2, amplify, lambda and serverless, nodejs, reactjs, Graphql, and nextis.
- Build applications used for refund services in America.

## **SENIOR FULL-STACK ENGINEER**

NY

(lamHoome)

March 2019-Dec 2019

- Developed full-stack application in nextjs, graphql, react-native, pusherjs for websockets, twilio for messaging, microservices with nodejs and laravel.
- Built Iamhoome application used for online health medication system in the US.
- Implemented video/audio call application on the browser using browser streams api, pusher js/peer js for peer-to-peer syncrhonization and twilio for real time video/audio streams.
- Implemented MailGun service for mailing
- Calendar management/ Doctor booking ui using nextjs, reactjs and graphql. (<u>iamhoome</u>)

#### SENIOR FULL-STACK ENGINEER

**ABUJA** 

(Access Solutions Nigeria Ltd.)

Aug 2015-Feb 2019

- Built scalable backend for Vuvaa application, an app used for fintech transactions and lifestyle activities.
- Deployed applications via proper ci/cd pipelines via aws cdk, dynamodb, amplify, cognito, lambda, S3 and cloudformation.
  (vuvaa)

#### SENIOR BLOCKCHAIN ENGINEER

- Built defi smart contracts using hardhat, on aave, and compound protocols on the Ethereum blockchain.
- Created and deployed an NFT ERC-721 smart contract for images. Also created an nft marketplace for buying, listing, and selling nft. With the option to deposit and withdraw funds in a decentralized manner.
- Built a DAO smart contract for autonomous and decentralized voting on Ethereum blockchain.
- Built a custom ERC-20 token to send and receive funds using blockchain (Smart Contracts)

#### **CORE FRONTEND SKILLS**

- Base Libraries/Frameworks: Reactis, Nextis, Vue, Angular, python
- Memory Storage Libriries: redux, vuex, angular universal
- Css/Scss Frameworks: Bootstrap, tailwind, jquery, mui, vuetify, angular material(Based on Google material Design architecture)

- Http Client: fetch api, axios with request interceptors, react-query, graphql and service workers
- Browser Storage: Localstorage, session storage, cookies
- Mobile App: React native, flutter, Java, Kotlin

#### **CORE BACKEND SKILLS**

- BASE SERVERS: Nodejs, express, Graphql, php, laravel, python, django, golang(intermediate)
- **ORM**: Mongoose, sequelize
- **RELATIONAL DATABASES**: mysql, mssql, mariadb, supabase
- NO SQL DATABASES: mongodb, aws dynamodb, firebase
- IAC: aws cdk, terraform, kubernetes(Intermediate level)

#### **BLOCKCHAIN SKILLS**

Evm compatible chains (Binance Smart Chain, Solana, Polygon), hardhat, Solidity, hardhat, ethers, web3, chainlink oracles, metamask, truffle, Alchemy, thirdweb, moralis, theGraph (Intermediate levels)

#### **DESIGN:**

Figma, Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Premier Pro, Adobe After Effect

#### **OTHERS:**

C++, Python, Java, c#

#### **DEVOPS SKILLS**

• Terraform, Aws Cdk, Kubernetes(intermediate), Azure, Google Cloud

## **EDUCATION**

•	First School Leaving Certificate	
	(St. John's Primary and Secondary international Schools, Maiduguri)	2001-2006
•	Senior Secondary School Certificate(O Level)	
	(St. Mary's Seminary Umuowa)	2006-2012
•	Barchelor of Science in Computer Science.	2014-2018
	(Abia State University Uturu)	

#### **EXTRAS**

•	I participated in the Cowbell National Mathematics Competition	2008
•	I participated in the National Computer Programming Contest Cup	2018

LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/luislawrence/

Github: <a href="https://github.com/villetrex">https://github.com/villetrex</a>

Twitter: https://twitter.com/luisvelawrence

#### LANGUAGES

- English (Proficient)
- Igbo
- Hausa